meetfranz.com 2019-04-23

# Privacy Statement

## Good to see you around here!

Franz is a free messaging app for Slack, Facebook Messenger, WhatsApp, Telegram and more. Since your communication is a very personal matter, the safety of your data is very important to us!

## 1\. Definitions

Franz is owned by Stefan Malzner (referred to as _"I"_ , _"Me"_ , _"We"_ or _"Our"_ ) and based in Vienna, Austria. As a customer of this service you're a _"User"_ or _"You"_ according to this agreement. The App or any services offered by us will be referred to as _"Franz"_ , _"Franz App"_ or just _"Service"_. External services like WhatsApp, Slack, etc will be referred to as _"External Providers"_ or _"External Services"_.

## 2\. Your Data

### External Services

It may not look like it, but Franz is actually very similar to a web browser and therefore does not need direct access to external service API's. That means that Franz does not store any of your external service login credentials on your computer or on a cloud service. The only data being stored are cookies and the browser cache – like when you’re using a web browser like Safari or Chrome.

By adding External Services to your very own Franz app, you accept their respective privacy policies. We have no control over how these services handle your data and it’s entirely up to you to decide which ones you trust.

**Franz does not store your password nor does it directly access your messaging service's account!**

### Franz Account

In order to save your configuration and provide features like settings synchronization or the Franz Premium Supporter plans, we require to store some data about you.

This data contains the following personal information:

  * Your name
  * Email address
  * Encrypted password
  * Organization/Company

We might occasionally contact you via email - when you want to reset your password, for example, or when we have big news that we want to share with you.

### Team Billing

With Team Billing, teams can be set up within Franz (duh!). In order to add new members to their team, team managers can send out invites via email. It is the team manager’s responsibility to ask new members for their permission before submitting their email address to Franz to send out an invite.

## 3\. Data portability

You can request an archive of the data we have stored about you. To file for such a request please login to your account [here](https://meetfranz.com/user/dashboard) and submit a data export request.

## 4\. Account Termination

You have the option to delete your personal data. To do so, please login [here](https://meetfranz.com/user/dashboard) and submit an account termination request.

Please understand that we can not delete your account for you - you’ll have to do it yourself. Why? We have no way of verifying if the person asking us to delete your account is actually you.

### Data Retention

If you haven't logged in to your Franz account within 550 days, we will automatically delete your account and all associated data.

## 5\. Cookies & Third Party Services

In order to provide certain features we rely on cookies and 3rd party services.

### Cookies

We use cookies to ensure you get the best experience on our website. For example, cookies help us check if you're already logged in, or if you're coming from an email invitation - or to make sure we don't bug you with our cookie banner every single time you revisit our website. Your IP address is anonymized and we don't store any personal data.

### Google Analytics

We do not track how you interact with any of the provided services. However, in order to build a better image of how our users are interacting with Franz and the Franz Website, we use Google Analytics to track how people work with Franz and what services are being used. We do not transmit personal data to Google Analytics.

### Recurly

If you decide to upgrade your account to a Franz Supporter Account or Enterprise Account, your name and email address will be transmitted to our payment provider [Recurly](https://recurly.com/). Details about how Recurly handles and secures your data can be found in the [Recurly Privacy Statement](https://recurly.com/legal/privacy).

If you wish to access, update/correct or request deletion of your personal data, you can do so [here](https://meetfranz.com/user/dashboard) or by contacting us.

You can always object to the processing of your personal data, please ask us to restrict processing of your personal data or request a data export. Again, you can do so [here](https://meetfranz.com/user/dashboard) or by contacting us.

You have the right to complain to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your personal data. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority.

## 7\. Changes

We reserve the right to update or modify this Privacy Policy from time to time without prior notice. Please review this document especially before you provide any information. This Privacy Policy was last updated on the date indicated below. Your continued use of the Services after any changes or revisions to this Privacy Policy shall indicate your agreement with the terms of such revised Privacy Policy.

## 8\. Questions

If you have any questions, comments or just want to say hi, feel free to write an email to hi@meetfranz.com

The last update to our Privacy Statement was posted on: 

The last update to this document was on 03.04.2019.
